{"tossups": [{"question": "This man was raised by a black slave named Hip\u00c3\u00b3lita, as he was orphaned at nine. On his deathbed, he asked his aide-de-camp, Daniel O'Leary, to burn his extensive library of his own writings and speeches, a request that was ignored. This man led forces meant to dismantle an administrative unit known as Real Audencia, which culminated in his victory at the 1822 battle of Pichincha. This man ascended as de facto dictator of an area formally known as New Granada in the Organic Decree. For 10 points, name this leader of Gran Colombia, the Liberator of South America.", "answer": "Simon Bolivar", "subcategory": "World History", "category": "History", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Simon Bolivar</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Simon Bolivar", "Simon Bolivar"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "ablo de Sarasate [sah-rah-SAH-tay] refused to play this composer's Violin Concerto because of the oboe solo in the Adagio second movement. This composer's second piano concerto contains a famous cello solo in the Andante third movement. This composer, who featured the violin and cello in his Double Concerto, wrote one piece after receiving an honorary doctorate. The nickname \"Beethoven's Tenth\" is given to this composer's first symphony. Another piece by this composer was written to celebrate the birth of Arthur and Bertha Faber's second child. For 10 points, name this German composer of the Academic Festival Overture and a famous lullaby. ", "answer": "Johannes Brahms ", "subcategory": "Auditory Fine Arts", "category": "Fine Arts", "answer_formatted": "Johannes <b><u>Brahms</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Johannes Brahms", "Brahms"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "In E.M. Forster's A Room with a View, Lucy Honeychurch breaks off her engagement to Cecil Vyse because he won't play this sport with her and Freddy. Humbert Humbert criticizes his step-daughter's playing of this game in Lolita. An essay in Esquire Magazine described Michael Joyce, a professional player of this sport, and was written by the American novelist who wrote of James Incandenza Junior's founding of Enfield Academy for teaching of this sport. FTP, David Foster Wallace often wrote about what sport, which was the focus of John McPhee's book Levels of the Game, which analyzed a match between Clark Graebner and Arthur Ashe, and which is currently played by Roger Federer?", "answer": "tennis", "subcategory": "Other Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>tennis</u></b>", "acceptable": ["tennis", "tennis"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "Along with a structure called the statolith, this compound names a hypothesis explaining how plants are able to sense gravity. Red algae have the floridian type of this compound, which names a synthase that catalyzes the reaction of ADP-glucose into adenosine diphosphate. The iodine test is used for the detection of this compound, the branched form of which is called amylopectin. The enzyme present in saliva breaks down this compound into maltose, and its animal analog is called glycogen. This polysaccharide has its glucose monomers in the alpha configuration, unlike cellulose. For 10 points, name this energy storage polysaccharide in plant cells.", "answer": "starch [or amylum] ", "subcategory": "Biology", "category": "Science", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>starch</u></b> [or <b><u>amylum</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["starch", "starch", "amylum"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "The Zaydi sect of this faith dominates Yemen and dates to an early split in this religious denomination. The title Aga Khan is bestowed on the leader of another sect of this denomination, the Nizari branch of the Ismailis. That group, also known as the Seveners, originated in a dispute over religious leadership with a group which followed Musa al-Khadim, known as the Twelvers. This sect is predominant in Iran. Belief in Ali as proper successor to Muhammad characterizes, FTP, what branch of Islam contrasted with Sunni?", "answer": "Shia Islam or Shi'ism (prompt on \"Islam\" before said; do NOT accept or prompt \t                   answer of \"Sunni\" Islam)", "category": "Religion", "subcategory": "Religion", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Shia Islam or Shi'ism</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Shia Islam or Shi'ism", "Shia Islam or Shi'ism"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": "prompt on \"Islam\" before said; do NOT accept or prompt \t                   answer of \"Sunni\" Islam"}, {"question": "In 1906, members of this ethnic group violently resisted the collection of a poll tax in the Bambatha Rebellion, during which Mohandas Gandhi offered the help of Indians as stretcher bearers for the British. The modern Inkatha Freedom Party was founded by these people, and its current leader is descended from the king who led these people to victory over the British at the Battle of Isandlwana. The most famous leader of this people created the iklwa, a short stabbing spear allegedly named for the sound it made entering a body. FTP what largest ethnicity of South Africa was once led by Shaka?", "answer": "Zulu", "subcategory": "Other History", "category": "History", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Zulu</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Zulu", "Zulu"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "The son of this deity lived in a hall with gold pillars and a silver ceiling called Glitnir and was a god of justice. Forseti's home was second in beauty only to Breidablik, this deity's gleaming mansion. This deity's wife was Nanna, who gave gifts for Hermod to bring back to Asgard at the same time this deity gave Hermod the ring Draupnir to return to Odin from Hel. This god's brother was the blind Hoder, who was tricked into shooting an arrow of mistletoe. FTP the death of what beautiful god from Norse myth brings on Ragnarok?", "answer": "Balder", "category": "Mythology", "subcategory": "Mythology", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Balder</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Balder", "Balder"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "A parody of this work by Banksy features a shirtless hooligan wearing Union Jack boxers who may have broken a window with some patio chairs. The right side of this painting includes a dull yellow ochre door and a mullion that partially blocks the view of one of the two coffee urns. Painted in 1942, this work includes an employee wearing a white uniform and a woman wearing a red dress. A sign above the central establishment in this painting advertises five cent cigars. For 10 points, name this Edward Hopper painting that depicts three customers at a diner. ", "answer": "Nighthawks ", "subcategory": "Visual Fine Arts", "category": "Fine Arts", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Nighthawks</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Nighthawks", "Nighthawks"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "This author depicted twins Lucien and Louis who can feel each other's pain over long distances because they were once conjoined in his novel The Corsican Brothers. Cardinal Mazarin sets the protagonist of an earlier novel by this author in search of his famous companions in a sequel by this author titled Twenty Years After. That novel by this author ends with a reunion of Athos, Porthos, Aramis, and D'artagnan. Another novel ends with Haydee setting off with the title character Edmond Dantes. FTP name this author of The Three Musketeers and The Count of Monte Cristo.", "answer": "Alexander Dumas, pere", "subcategory": "European Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "Alexander Dumas, <b><u>pere</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Alexander Dumas, pere", "pere"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "Biological examples of these chemical substances include plants such as Blackstonia perfoliata and the common heather. One of these chemical substances, formerly used as a laxative, was first prepared using the reaction of phthalic [THAL-ik] anhydride with two equivalents of phenol in the presence of sulfuric acid. Along with a dye, one of these substances can be easily made using red cabbage leaves. The \"universal\" one of these substances makes use of thymol blue and methyl red. Other examples of these substances include phenolphthalein [fee-nawl-THAL-een] and litmus. For 10 points, name these substances that change colors at the equivalence point in a titration. ", "answer": "indicators", "subcategory": "Chemistry", "category": "Science", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>indicators</u></b>", "acceptable": ["indicators", "indicators"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "The Three-North Shelterbelt Program was created to curb the desertification of this desert. The world's only desert-dwelling bear lives in this desert, along with other wildlife such as the Bactrian camel and Marble Polecats. The eastern steppes of this desert also hosts the Yin Mountains, while the Tian Shan Mountains separate this desert's Dzungarian basin from the Taklamakan Desert. For 10 points, name this East Asian desert that lies in Northwestern China and Southern Mongolia", "answer": "Gobi Desert", "category": "Geography", "subcategory": "Geography", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Gobi</u></b> Desert", "acceptable": ["Gobi Desert", "Gobi"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "This man was considered a surrogate son of the Speaker of the House, Sam Rayburn. After two years of service in World War II, this man returned to the Senate and was made head of the Naval Affairs Committee. This man ironically formed the \"Stop Kennedy\" coalition in 1960 with Adlai Stevenson and Hubert Humphrey. As president, he had a set of domestic programs known as the Great Society. \u00c2\u00a0For 10 points, name this Texan who was chosen to be Kennedy's running mate in the election of 1960.", "answer": "Lyndon B. Johnson (Accept LBJ, prompt on Johnson)", "subcategory": "American History", "category": "History", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Lyndon B. Johnson</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Lyndon B. Johnson", "Lyndon B. Johnson"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": "Accept LBJ, prompt on Johnson"}, {"question": "One collection of Wallace Stevens's essays is titled for the \"necessary\" one of these beings. \u00c2\u00a0In \"A Supermarket in California, Allen Ginsberg imagines Walt Whitman asking a grocery boy, \"Are you my [one of these beings]? One novel partly titled for one of these beings depicts the childhood of Eugene Gant in the fictional town of Altamont and was written by Thomas Wolfe; the title of that work tells this type of being to \"Look Homeward.\" FTP, a 1993 Tony Kushner play subtitled \"A Gay Fantasia on National Themes\" is titled for what type of celestial being \"in America\"?", "answer": "angels", "subcategory": "American Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>angels</u></b>", "acceptable": ["angels", "angels"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "A temple on this island that contains a \"hidden foot\" is composed of six square platforms topped by three circular ones and also includes seventy-two stupas. Banten is the westernmost province on this island, which is home to the active volcano Mount Merapi and the Borobudur temple. \u00c2\u00a0Eugene Dubois discovered a specimen of Homo erectus on this island, which is the most populous in the world. Located in between Sumatra and Bali, this island contains its country's capital city. For 10 points, name this Indonesian island that is home to Jakarta and names a variety of coffee.", "answer": "Java", "category": "Geography", "subcategory": "Geography", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Java</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Java", "Java"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "The intensity of these objects can be measured on the twelve-point Papadopoulos-Imamura scale. One of these objects led to the somewhat recent rediscovery of relics at Mahabalipuram [muh-HAH-buh-lee-poo-ruhm]. The assessment and reporting of these objects, which can be as small as a couple of centimeters, is made with the DART system. A warning sign for one of these objects is a phenomenon called a drawback, although early detection of them is difficult because of shoaling. These objects can have a height of 100 feet, and their name is Japanese for \"harbor wave.\" For 10 points, name these very large waves produced by landslides, earthquakes or volcanic activity. ", "answer": "tsunamis [be nice and prompt on \"tidal wave\"] ", "subcategory": "Other Science", "category": "Science", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>tsunamis</u></b> [be nice and prompt on \"tidal wave\"]", "acceptable": ["tsunamis", "tsunamis"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "According to VSEPR theory, this molecular geometry is possessed by the tri-iodide anion, in which the central iodine atom is bonded to two other iodines and three lone pairs. In this type of mathematical programming, the simplex algorithm is efficient at solving most problems. Molecular orbitals can be expressed as this type of combination of atomic orbitals. This word names a branch of algebra concerned with matrices and vector spaces. VSEPR theory also predicts that carbon dioxide, with bond angles of 180 degrees, has this molecular geometry. For 10 points, name this word that names equations of the first degree, which can be written in slope-intercept form. ", "answer": "linear", "subcategory": "Other Science", "category": "Science", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>linear</u></b>", "acceptable": ["linear", "linear"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "This team was outscored 27-0 in the fourth quarter of the 1934 championship game after the Giants switched to sneakers. This team used the T-formation in its 73-0 victory over the Redskins in the 1940 championship game. James Caan and Billy Dee Williams played the main characters in a 1971 made-for-TV movie about two running backs on this team, which was coached in the '40s and '50s by George Halas. Brian Piccolo and Gale Sayers were former members of this team that later included William \"Refrigerator\" Perry and Walter Payton. For 10 points, name this NFL team whose players recorded \"The Super Bowl Shuffle\" before winning the 1985 Super Bowl and is currently quarterbacked by Jay Cutler.", "answer": "Chicago Bears [accept either] ", "category": "Trash", "subcategory": "Trash", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Chicago Bears</u></b> [accept <b><u>either</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["Chicago Bears", "Chicago Bears", "either"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "Along with Rufus King, this man wrote a series of essays in support of Jay's Treaty using the pseudonym Camillus. This man was the only one from his state to sign the Constitution because John Lansing, Jr. and Robert Yates were not present. This man discussed the national government assuming state debts and paying back the war bonds from the Revolutionary War in his \"Report on Public Credit.\" This man also wrote 51 of the 85 of the installments of The Federalist Papers, with the others written by John Jay and John Madison. For 10 points, name this man who was the first Secretary of the Treasury and was killed in a duel by Aaron Burr.", "answer": "Alexander Hamilton ", "subcategory": "American History", "category": "History", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Alexander Hamilton</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Alexander Hamilton", "Alexander Hamilton"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "This building is located in the background of Bouguereau's painting The Bohemian, and a painting by Matisse shows it \"in the late afternoon.\" Leonin and Perotin were members of a school of polyphony named for this building, which is home to the Emmanuel bell. Eugene Viollet-le-Duc restored this building in the 19th century, which is when Victor Pyanet sculpted the gargoyles that adorn it. This building is located on the Ile de la Cite, and its nave may have been the first in the world with exterior flying buttresses. For 10 points, name this Gothic cathedral located in Paris. ", "answer": "Notre Dame [do NOT accept answers mentioning cities other than Paris] ", "subcategory": "Other Fine Arts", "category": "Fine Arts", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Notre Dame</u></b> [do NOT accept answers mentioning cities other than Paris]", "acceptable": ["Notre Dame", "Notre Dame"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "One event of this type was preceded by the drawing of a magic circle by Ea around himself and his siblings and followed by the creation of humans from clay. The Pleiades were tricked into taking this action by Medea, who demonstrated that putting the chopped up pieces of an old ram into a cauldron and boiling it would create a young ram. Blood that came from one of these actions created the Furies and the Giants, while the testicles of the victim created the foam that birthed Aphrodite. Ea conducted this action against Apsu, just as Cronus did to Uranus. FTP what action was also unwittingly committed by Oedipus when he killed Laius?", "answer": "patricide or killing one's father (prompt on \"murder\" or \"killing\" but be lenient on \u00c2\u00a0\u00c2\u00a0\u00c2\u00a0\u00c2\u00a0\u00c2\u00a0\u00c2\u00a0\u00c2\u00a0\u00c2\u00a0\u00c2\u00a0\u00c2\u00a0\u00c2\u00a0\u00c2\u00a0\u00c2\u00a0\u00c2\u00a0\u00c2\u00a0\u00c2\u00a0\u00c2\u00a0\u00c2\u00a0\u00c2\u00a0\u00c2\u00a0\u00c2\u00a0\u00c2\u00a0 \u00c2\u00a0\u00c2\u00a0\u00c2\u00a0\u00c2\u00a0 reasonable alternatives)", "category": "Mythology", "subcategory": "Mythology", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>patricide or killing one's father</u></b>", "acceptable": ["patricide or killing one's father", "patricide or killing one's father"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": "prompt on \"murder\" or \"killing\" but be lenient on \u00c2\u00a0\u00c2\u00a0\u00c2\u00a0\u00c2\u00a0\u00c2\u00a0\u00c2\u00a0\u00c2\u00a0\u00c2\u00a0\u00c2\u00a0\u00c2\u00a0\u00c2\u00a0\u00c2\u00a0\u00c2\u00a0\u00c2\u00a0\u00c2\u00a0\u00c2\u00a0\u00c2\u00a0\u00c2\u00a0\u00c2\u00a0\u00c2\u00a0\u00c2\u00a0\u00c2\u00a0 \u00c2\u00a0\u00c2\u00a0\u00c2\u00a0\u00c2\u00a0 reasonable alternatives"}, {"question": "The 18th-century economist Jacques Turgot conceptualized a theory of \"fructification\" stating that the rate for this entity must always be positive. In the 1930s, Robertson and Ohlin added bank credit to the equation for determining its rate, adding to its two classical components of savings and investment. Middle Eastern banks following Sharia declare this entity to be \"riba,\" and thus prohibit it under Islamic law. FTP what is this charge levied by lenders on money clients borrow?", "answer": "interest (rate)", "category": "Social Science", "subcategory": "Social Science", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>interest</u></b>", "acceptable": ["interest", "interest"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": "rate"}, {"question": "An automaton created to participate in this activity kills its creator in the Ambrose Bierce short story \"Moxon's Master.\" Repetitions of the barman's closing cry of \"HURRY UP PLEASE IT'S TIME\" appear in a section named for this game that is the second part of Eliot's \"The Waste Land.\" A short story by Kurt Vonnegut depicts an American playing this game with his Chinese captor for his and his family's life. That story, \"All the King's Horses,\" depicts, FTP, what game at which Vladimir Nabokov was an expert player and was featured in his novel The Defense?", "answer": "chess", "subcategory": "Other Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>chess</u></b>", "acceptable": ["chess", "chess"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "This man was the aggressor in the War of Devolution, which took place after the death of King Philip IV of Spain. His \"Black Code\" allowed slavery, but did not allow the separation of black families. This man made a covert deal with the English known as the secret Treaty of Dover. This man and his ministers were responsible for enacting the Edict of Fontainebleau, which revoked the Edict of Nantes signed by Henry the IV a century before. For 10 points, name this royal who built the Palace of Versailles and was known as the \"Sun King.\"", "answer": "Louis XIV (prompt on Sun King before read) ", "subcategory": "European History", "category": "History", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Louis XIV</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Louis XIV", "Louis XIV"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": "prompt on Sun King before read"}, {"question": "This singer was called \"Judas\" by a concertgoer in London, which was shown in a D. A. Pennebaker documentary. One song by this subject of Don't Look Back asks \"Something is happening here / But you don't know what it is / Do you, Mr. Jones?\" and might be about a naive journalist. This man's song \"Ballad of a Thin Man\" appears on his album Highway 61 Revisited, and at a music festival in Newport, fellow folk singer Pete Seeger allegedly tried to cut the power cable to his instrument. For 10 points, name this signer who \"went electric\" in 1965 and recorded songs such as \"Mr. Tambourine Man,\" \"Like a Rolling Stone\" and \"Blowin' in the Wind.\"", "answer": "Bob Dylan [or Robert Allen Zimmerman] ", "category": "Trash", "subcategory": "Trash", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Bob Dylan</u></b> [or <b><u>Robert Allen Zimmerman</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["Bob Dylan", "Bob Dylan", "Robert Allen Zimmerman"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "During this war, the Battle of Wistock saw an allied army under John Baner and Alexander Leslie defeat an army under John George I. One side in this conflict signed the Treaty of Stettin to occupy the Duchy of Pomerania. The Treaty of Lubeck ended the Danish phase of this conflict, which allowed Christian IV to retain Denmark in exchange for abandoning support for the Protestant States. The Swedish phase of this war was ended after Gustavus Adolphus died at the Battle of Lutzen. For 10 points, name this 17th century conflict that began with the Second Defenestration of Prague and ended with the Peace of Westphalia.", "answer": "The Thirty Years' War", "subcategory": "European History", "category": "History", "answer_formatted": "The <b><u>Thirty Years' War</u></b>", "acceptable": ["The Thirty Years' War", "Thirty Years' War"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "One work by this author, subtitled \"A Book for Free Spirits,\" includes an opening section noting it was begun at the Bayreuth festival of music. Human, All Too Human precedes a work by this author that includes a passage titled \"The Greatest Weight\" which asks whether one would celebrate as a god a demon who announced that one would have to relive his life over the exact same way infinitely many times. That is this thinker's idea of eternal recurrence. FTP what German philosopher had a madman pronounce that \"God is dead\" in The Gay Science?", "answer": "Friedrich Nietzsche", "category": "Philosophy", "subcategory": "Philosophy", "answer_formatted": "Friedrich <b><u>Nietzsche</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Friedrich Nietzsche", "Nietzsche"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "A book by this man imagines hypothetical splurge-weed and bottle-wrack seaweed. Fred Hoyle's image of a storm sweeping through a scrapyard inspired this man's Ultimate Boeing 747 gambit. Another book by this man includes recursive figures called biomorphs and takes its title from a William Paley argument. A memoir by this man discusses the \"two chairs effect\" and his recent refusal to formally debate creationists. This author of The Blind Watchmaker named the green-beard effect and also coined the term meme. For 10 points, name this Oxford professor whose books about atheism and evolutionary biology include The God Delusion and The Selfish Gene. ", "answer": "Richard Dawkins ", "subcategory": "Other Science", "category": "Science", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Richard Dawkins</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Richard Dawkins", "Richard Dawkins"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "For a tube open at one end and closed at the other, the wavelength of the first harmonic equals the length of the pipe times this number. In a fluid, the volume flow rate is proportional to the radius raised to this power in Poiseuille's [pwah-ZWEEZ] law. Rounded to the nearest whole number of degrees Celsius, the density of water is greatest at this temperature. An atom's mass number decreases by this value when alpha decay occurs. Including the zeroth, there is this number of laws of thermodynamics. For 10 points, name this number of space-time dimensions.", "answer": "four [accept obvious equivalents, such as fourth] ", "subcategory": "Other Science", "category": "Science", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>four</u></b> [accept <b><u>obvious equivalents, such as fourth</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["four", "four", "obvious equivalents, such as fourth"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "This animal appears in the title of a novel in which a chauffeur writes letters to Wen Jiabao about how he murdered his employer. This animal also appears in the interrogative title of a short story in which a king uses a method of justice that ends in either a brutal slaughter or a wedding. Rudyard Kipling created one of these animals named Shere Khan, and in the Yann Martel novel Life of Pi, the character Richard Parker is one of these animals. For 10 points, name this animal that titles a poem in which it is \"Burning bright / In the forests of the night.\"", "answer": "tiger", "subcategory": "Other Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>tiger</u></b>", "acceptable": ["tiger", "tiger"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "It's not personality, but psychologist Henri Tajfel (tah-ful) studied the social construction of this concept, placing this concept in the middle of an evaluation process of others beginning with categorization and ending with comparison. A fragmentation of this concept was called \"Multiple Personality Disorder\" until the most recent Diagnostic and Statistical Manual. An Austrian psychologist characterized one stage of psychosocial development as posing this concept against role confusion. FTP Erik Erikson argued that failure to develop what sense of self-definition could lead to a namesake crisis?", "answer": "identity (prompt on \"personality\" before mentioned, even though it's really wrong)", "category": "Social Science", "subcategory": "Social Science", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>identity</u></b>", "acceptable": ["identity", "identity"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": "prompt on \"personality\" before mentioned, even though it's really wrong"}, {"question": "One character created by this author is an acrophobic architect who falls to his death from a church steeple after being encouraged to climb it by Hilde. Halvard Solness appears in this writer's The Master Builder. Another of his characters convinces Eilert Lovborg to kill himself, but when Judge Brack blackmails her, she also kills herself. This creator of Hedda Gabler also depicted a woman who leaves behind her wedding ring before famously slamming the door behind her as she leaves her husband Torvald Helmer. FTP what Norwegian playwright wrote of Nora Helmer in A Doll's House?", "answer": "Henrik Ibsen", "subcategory": "European Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Henrik Ibsen</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Henrik Ibsen", "Henrik Ibsen"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "One of the first English-language examinations of this philosophy was William Barrett's 1962 book Irrational Man. An important concept in this philosophy is the part of oneself unavailable to his consciousness, called facticity. A foundational text in this philosophy presents an example of a waiter who exhibits \"bad faith\" by seeing himself only as a waiter, confusing his being-in-itself with being-for-itself. FTP what philosophy was described as \"a Humanism\" by the author of Being and Nothingness, Jean-Paul Sartre?", "answer": "existentialism", "category": "Philosophy", "subcategory": "Philosophy", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>existentialism</u></b>", "acceptable": ["existentialism", "existentialism"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "At the end of this song, one person encourages the listener to \"Do the muscle\" and \"Rock away.\"In this song, one person has a pinky valued at over three hundred thousand, and another is rated, on a scale of one to ten, a \"certified twenty.\" This song features Ludacris, who declares his desire for \"a lady in the street but a freak in the bed.\" This song, which precedes \"Throwback\" on the album Confessions, also features Lil John, who repeatedly exclaims \"Watch out,\" \"Let's go,\" \"Hey,\" \"Okay,\" and the titular word. For 10 points, name this 2004 song by Usher.", "answer": "Yeah!", "category": "Trash", "subcategory": "Trash", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Yeah!</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Yeah!", "Yeah!"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "One leader in this event asked Gilbert Burnet, \"Well, Doctor, what do you think of predestination now?\" after landing his forces at Brixham. A letter written by Henry Sidney led to this conflict, and one side in this conflict was supported by the Immortal Seven. The losing side in this conflict was later defeated in the Battle of the Boyne during the First Jacobite Rising. This conflict was triggered when Mary of Modena gave birth to a boy, spurring Protestant fears of a Roman Catholic heir to the throne. \u00c2\u00a0Ending the reign of James II, FTP, name this 1688 revolution that put William and Mary on the throne of England.", "answer": "Glorious Revolution", "subcategory": "European History", "category": "History", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Glorious</u></b> Revolution", "acceptable": ["Glorious Revolution", "Glorious"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "A woman who engages in this practice is sometimes called a kosayayani, or \"owl-like one,\" by Buddhists. One Hindu scripture proposes that a woman who engages in this practice, called samagraha, becomes pure at her next menses. Jibreel showed Muhammad people tormented in hell by having inflated bodies and emitting terrible smells for taking part in zina, the Arabic term for this sin. Matthew 5:28 states that he who simply looks upon another with lust commits this sin in his heart. FTP what is this act of cheating on one's spouse?", "answer": "adultery (accept reasonable equivalents before last sentence) ", "category": "Religion", "subcategory": "Religion", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>adultery</u></b>", "acceptable": ["adultery", "adultery"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": "accept reasonable equivalents before last sentence"}, {"question": "This element's sulfate is reduced by iron in its namesake \"beating heart\" reaction. A bay in Japan containing wastewater from the Chisso Corporation chemical factory names a disease caused by its methylated form. Dartmouth chemistry professor Karen Wetterhahn died when a drop of the di-methylated form of this element penetrated her skin. This element's chloride, which is used as a standard reference electrode, is called calomel. The primary ore of this element is called cinnabar, and the alloys of this element are known as amalgams. For 10 points, name this metal element that is liquid at room temperature, and has the chemical symbol Hg. ", "answer": "mercury [accept Hg before mentioned]  ", "subcategory": "Chemistry", "category": "Science", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>mercury</u></b> [accept <b><u>Hg</u></b> before mentioned]", "acceptable": ["mercury", "mercury", "Hg"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "Until the 1920's, indigenous people of this nation, including the Burakumin, were known as \"internal others.\" This nation was home to an all-female theatre group which included the \"Star Troupe\" and \"Cosmos Troupe.\" While this nation had an embargo on most of the world, it developed the economy using the \"Dutch Learning\" system. Men in this nation were able to freely take jobs in cities during a period of modernization under its Charter Oath. Rulers of this nation were supported by regional princes known as daimyo until the 1860's. For 10 points, identify this nation which changed its capital from Edo to Tokyo.", "answer": "Japan [or Nippon]", "subcategory": "World History", "category": "History", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Japan</u></b> [or <b><u>Nippon</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["Japan", "Japan", "Nippon"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "This quantity for a particle in a box is zero inside the box and infinity at the walls. In a form of the virial equation, the time average of this quantity is multiplied by negative one-half. For a magnetic dipole, this quantity equals the negative dot product of the magnetic moment and magnetic field. For a fully compressed spring, the elastic form of it equals one half k x-squared. The gravitational form of this quantity, which is symbolized by a capital U, equals m times g times h. For 10 points, name this quantity that is the energy an object possesses due to its position, rather than motion. ", "answer": "potential energy [prompt on \"energy;\" do NOT accept \"kinetic energy\"] ", "subcategory": "Physics", "category": "Science", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>potential energy</u></b> [prompt on <u>energy</u>; \" do NOT accept \"kinetic energy\"]", "acceptable": ["potential energy", "potential"], "promptable": ["energy"], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "In this novel, a cryptic postcard reading \"U.P. up\" causes Dennis Breen much mental distress. One protagonist of this novel masturbates while watching Gerty MacDowell lift her skirts, knowing he's watching her, during a fireworks show in a section parodying 19th-century Romantic novels. In a section evoking the shape-shifter Proteus, another protagonist of this novel wonders if he is \"walking into eternity down Sandymount Strand\" after having an argument with Buck Mulligan on June 16, 1904. Molly Bloom's soliloquy ends, FTP, what dense novel about the symbolic father-son relationship of Leopold Bloom and Stephen Dedalus written by James Joyce and based on Homer's Odyssey?", "answer": "Ulysses", "subcategory": "British Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Ulysses</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Ulysses", "Ulysses"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "A city in this country provides the setting of James Kelman's Booker Prize-winning novel How Late It Was, How Late. The \"housing schemes\" of another city in this country are the backdrop for Renton and Sick Boy's hustling for heroin in a 1993 novel by Irvine Welsh that was turned into a movie by Danny Boyle. The unofficial national poet of this country noted that \"the best known schemes o' mice an' men/Gang aft agley\" in \"To a Mouse.\" That poet is Robert Burns. Kelman used the Glaswegian dialect of what country, FTP, in which Trainspotting took place in Edinburgh.", "answer": "Scotland (Prompt on \"United Kingdom\" or \"Great Britain\"; do not accept \"England\")", "subcategory": "European Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Scotland</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Scotland", "Scotland"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": "Prompt on \"United Kingdom\" or \"Great Britain\"; do not accept \"England\""}], "bonuses": [{"leadin": "In the 19th century, Cesare [CHE-zah-rey] Lombroso believed he could identify people who would perpetrate this action by their atavistic qualities. FTPE:", "answers": ["crime", "deviance", "Emile Durkheim"], "parts": ["Sociologists define what term as a violation of social norms that specifically involves breaking the law?", "This term characterizes behaviors that are not crime but violate social norms, mores, or taboos. The term itself suggests it means behaviors that are off the normal path.", "This French sociologist argued that crime is a necessary social function because it reinforces social mores. He also studied suicide and wrote The Division of Labor in Society."], "subcategory": "Social Science", "category": "Social Science", "answers_formatted": ["<b><u>crime</u></b>", "<b><u>deviance</u></b>", "<b><u>Emile Durkheim</u></b>"], "acceptable": [["crime", "crime"], ["deviance", "deviance"], ["Emile Durkheim", "Emile Durkheim"]], "promptable": [[], [], []], "rejectable": [[], [], []], "metadata": ["", "", ""]}, {"leadin": "This poet extolled the beauty of \u201cLesbia,\u201d who was based on the sister of P. Clodius Pulcher. FTPE:", "answers": ["Gaius Valerius Catullus", "Latin", "Sappho"], "parts": ["What classical poet lamented the loss of his brother in a poem ending \u201cAve atque vale\u201d?", "Catullus wrote in this language used by Vergil for The Aeneid.", "Catullus\u2019s use of \u201cLesbia\u201d to refer to Clodia evokes this earlier Greek poet from the island of Lesbos who was hailed as the \u201cTenth Muse.\u201d"], "subcategory": "Classical Literature", "category": "Literature", "answers_formatted": ["<b><u>Gaius Valerius Catullus</u></b>", "<b><u>Latin</u></b>", "<b><u>Sappho</u></b>"], "acceptable": [["Gaius Valerius Catullus", "Gaius Valerius Catullus"], ["Latin", "Latin"], ["Sappho", "Sappho"]], "promptable": [[], [], []], "rejectable": [[], [], []], "metadata": ["", "", ""]}, {"leadin": "Commandos who stormed a hijacked Belgian plane in 1972 included two future holders of this political position. FTPE:", "answers": ["Prime Minister of Israel", "Golda Meir", "Yitzhak Rabin"], "parts": ["What national leadership position was held by Ehud Barak from 1999 to 2001 and is currently held by ice cream fanatic Benjamin Netanyahu?", "This only woman to be Prime Minister of Israel called for Operation Wrath of God to hunt down terrorists who killed Jewish athletes at the 1972 Olympics.", "This man\u2019s second stint as Prime Minister was ended with his assassination by an ultranationalist who was angry about Israel\u2019s agreement to the Oslo Accords in 1995."], "subcategory": "World History", "category": "History", "answers_formatted": ["<b><u>Prime Minister of Israel</u></b>", "<b><u>Golda Meir</u></b>", "<b><u>Yitzhak Rabin</u></b>"], "acceptable": [["Prime Minister of Israel", "Prime Minister of Israel"], ["Golda Meir", "Golda Meir"], ["Yitzhak Rabin", "Yitzhak Rabin"]], "promptable": [[], [], []], "rejectable": [[], [], []], "metadata": ["", "", ""]}, {"leadin": "Some mines in Gabon were a naturally occurring site of it around two billion years ago. FTPE:", "answers": ["nuclear fission", "neutrons", "Cherenkov radiation"], "parts": ["Name this process in which a nucleus breaks up into two lighter ones, the opposite of fusion.", "Fission is slowed down by control rods, which absorb these particles. Discovered by James Chadwick, they decay into protons, electrons, and electron anti-neutrinos in beta minus decay.", "This blue glow in the water surrounding the core of a nuclear reactor is produced by charged particles passing through a transparent medium at a speed faster than light."], "subcategory": "Chemistry", "category": "Science", "answers_formatted": ["<b><u>nuclear fission</u></b>", "<b><u>neutrons</u></b>", "<b><u>Cherenkov radiation</u></b>"], "acceptable": [["nuclear fission", "nuclear fission"], ["neutrons", "neutrons"], ["Cherenkov radiation", "Cherenkov radiation"]], "promptable": [[], [], []], "rejectable": [[], [], []], "metadata": ["", "", ""]}, {"leadin": "Picander wrote the libretto to this work, which was scored for double choir and double orchestra, contains the aria \"Erbarme dich,\" and was written for a Good Friday service. For 10 points each:", "answers": ["St Matthew Passion [or St Matthew's Passion; or Matthaus-Passion]", "Johann Sebastian Bach", "Felix Mendelssohn"], "parts": ["Name this 1727 sacred oratorio whose narrative is taken from its namesake's gospel.", "Along with the St Matthew Passion, this German composed the Brandenburg Concertos.", "This fellow German performed a version of the St Matthew Passion in 1829, which revived interest in J. S. Bach's music. His own works include the Italian and Scottish symphonies."], "subcategory": "Auditory Fine Arts", "category": "Fine Arts", "answers_formatted": ["<b><u>St Matthew Passion</u></b> [or <b><u>St Matthew's Passion</u></b>; or <b><u>Matthaus-Passion</u></b>]", "<b><u>Johann Sebastian Bach</u></b>", "<b><u>Felix Mendelssohn</u></b>"], "acceptable": [["St Matthew Passion", "St Matthew Passion", "St Matthew's Passion", "Matthaus-Passion"], ["Johann Sebastian Bach", "Johann Sebastian Bach"], ["Felix Mendelssohn", "Felix Mendelssohn"]], "promptable": [[], [], []], "rejectable": [[], [], []], "metadata": ["", "", ""]}, {"leadin": "J. M. E. McTaggert argued for the \u201cunreality\u201d of this concept. FTPE:", "answers": ["time", "free will", "memory"], "parts": ["What is this concept, the mental experience of which Henri Bergson linked with \u201cduree,\u201d [durr-ay] or \u201cduration,\u201d in English?", "Bergson titled a book for time and this other concept, which most people associate with a human ability to choose to do whatever he wishes; this concept is opposed by determinism.", "Bergson associated this other human faculty with duree, arguing that it is greater than just a consciousness of a collection of events. He paired this term with the word Matter in an 1896 book."], "subcategory": "Philosophy", "category": "Philosophy", "answers_formatted": ["<b><u>time</u></b>", "<b><u>free will</u></b>", "<b><u>memory</u></b>"], "acceptable": [["time", "time"], ["free will", "free will"], ["memory", "memory"]], "promptable": [[], [], []], "rejectable": [[], [], []], "metadata": ["", "", ""]}, {"leadin": "This election first gained major prominence when Dwight Eisenhower upset Robert Taft in 1952. FTPE:", "answers": ["New Hampshire", "Bob Dole", "caucus"], "parts": ["What state\u2019s primary, including the town vote held by its town of Dixville Notch, is traditionally the first held by both major parties?", "In 1996, Pat Buchanan shocked this eventual Republican nominee by winning the New Hampshire primary. This Kansas senator eventually got stomped by Bill Clinton.", "New Hampshire law requires it to hold the first primary election in the US process, but Iowa residents actually vote first, but in this type of open voting process that only selects delegates to county conventions."], "subcategory": "American History", "category": "History", "answers_formatted": ["<b><u>New Hampshire</u></b>", "<b><u>Bob Dole</u></b>", "<b><u>caucus</u></b>"], "acceptable": [["New Hampshire", "New Hampshire"], ["Bob Dole", "Bob Dole"], ["caucus", "caucus"]], "promptable": [[], [], []], "rejectable": [[], [], []], "metadata": ["", "", ""]}, {"leadin": "Novelist Roberto Bola\u00f1o lived till age 15 in this country and wrote a book titled \u201cBy Night in [this country]. FTPE:", "answers": ["Chile", "Pablo Neruda", "Macchu Picchu"], "parts": ["What South American country also produced the author of The House of the Spirits, Isabel Allende?", "As nearly every quiz bowl tournament will remind you, this Chilean poet repeats the line \u201cin you everything sank\u201d in his \u201cSong of Despair, which he paired with twenty love songs.", "Neruda wrote that \u201cLives like maize were threshed in the bottomless/granary of wasted deeds\u201d in a poem named for the \u201cheights of\u201d this Inca city."], "subcategory": "World Literature", "category": "Literature", "answers_formatted": ["<b><u>Chile</u></b>", "<b><u>Pablo Neruda</u></b>", "<b><u>Macchu Picchu</u></b>"], "acceptable": [["Chile", "Chile"], ["Pablo Neruda", "Pablo Neruda"], ["Macchu Picchu", "Macchu Picchu"]], "promptable": [[], [], []], "rejectable": [[], [], []], "metadata": ["", "", ""]}, {"leadin": "In the Mahabharata, Nakula and Sahadeva share this relationship. FTPE:", "answers": ["twins", "Arjuna", "fire"], "parts": ["Those siblings share what special relationship, also shared by Castor and Pollux?", "Nakula and Sahadeva are younger brothers of this third Pandava brother, who is exhorted to fight his cousins by Krishna in the Bhagavad Gita.", "In Aztec myth, Quetzalcoatl\u2019s twin Xolotl [zoh-lotul] is a god of this substance, as is Agni in Hindu myth."], "subcategory": "Mythology", "category": "Mythology", "answers_formatted": ["<b><u>twins</u></b>", "<b><u>Arjuna</u></b>", "<b><u>fire</u></b>"], "acceptable": [["twins", "twins"], ["Arjuna", "Arjuna"], ["fire", "fire"]], "promptable": [[], [], []], "rejectable": [[], [], []], "metadata": ["", "", ""]}, {"leadin": "The wavelength of these objects is approximately the distance between atoms in a crystal, which allowed them to be used by Rosalind Franklin in a namesake type of crystallography. FTPE:", "answers": ["X-rays [or X-radiation]", "Wilhelm Rontgen [RENT-guhn]", "Bragg's law"], "parts": ["Name these electromagnetic waves that are also used in medicine to take pictures of bones.", "X-rays were discovered in 1895 by this German physicist, the namesake of element 111.", "X-ray crystallography can be described by this eponymous law, which states two times the lattice spacing times the scattering angle equals integer multiples of the wavelength."], "subcategory": "Chemistry", "category": "Science", "answers_formatted": ["<b><u>X-rays</u></b> [or <b><u>X-radiation</u></b>]", "<b><u>Wilhelm Rontgen</u></b> [RENT-guhn]", "<b><u>Bragg's</u></b> law"], "acceptable": [["X-rays", "X-rays", "X-radiation"], ["Wilhelm Rontgen", "Wilhelm Rontgen"], ["Bragg's law", "Bragg's"]], "promptable": [[], [], []], "rejectable": [[], [], []], "metadata": ["", "", ""]}, {"leadin": "Bill Baroni and Bridget Anne Kelly are awaiting trial for their roles in this scandal. FTPE:", "answers": ["Bridgegate", "Chris Christie", "United"], "parts": ["Name this scandal in which lanes on a structure named for George Washington in Fort Lee were closed in 2013 in order to create traffic jams and retaliate against a Democratic mayor.", "Bridgegate is one of many controversies surrounding the administration of this New Jersey governor, who had the audacity to embrace President Obama shortly after Hurricane Sandy.", "Jeff Smisek resigned as this airline\u2019s CEO amid a probe into a money-losing flight from Newark to Columbia, South Carolina, near where Christie ally David Samson has a home."], "subcategory": "Current Events", "category": "Current Events", "answers_formatted": ["<b><u>Bridgegate</u></b>", "<b><u>Chris Christie</u></b>", "<b><u>United</u></b>"], "acceptable": [["Bridgegate", "Bridgegate"], ["Chris Christie", "Chris Christie"], ["United", "United"]], "promptable": [[], [], []], "rejectable": [[], [], []], "metadata": ["", "", ""]}, {"leadin": "This film won the 2013 Palme d\u2019Or and is based on a Julie Maroh graphic novel. FTPE:", "answers": ["Blue Is the Warmest Color [prompt on \"La Vie d'Adele\" or \"Adele\"]", "France", "Pierre-Auguste Renoir"], "parts": ["Identify the English title of this film in which Emma and Adele have lots of lesbian sex.", "Blue Is the Warmest Color is set in this European country, the birthplace of the New Wave directors Jean-Luc Godard and Francois Truffaut.", "The film The Rules of the Game was directed by the son of this French artist, whose painting Luncheon of the Boating Party is copied annually by The Glass Man in the movie Amelie."], "subcategory": "Other Fine Arts", "category": "Fine Arts", "answers_formatted": ["<b><u>Blue Is the Warmest Color</u></b> [prompt on <u>La Vie d'Adele</u> or <u>Adele</u>]", "<b><u>France</u></b>", "<b><u>Pierre-Auguste Renoir</u></b>"], "acceptable": [["Blue Is the Warmest Color", "Blue Is the Warmest Color"], ["France", "France"], ["Pierre-Auguste Renoir", "Pierre-Auguste Renoir"]], "promptable": [["La Vie d'Adele", "Adele"], [], []], "rejectable": [[], [], []], "metadata": ["", "", ""]}, {"leadin": "This biblical patriarch begat 12 sons who established the twelve tribes of Israel. FTPE:", "answers": ["Jacob or Israel", "Joseph", "Dinah"], "parts": ["What Old Testament figure was born holding onto the heel of his older twin brother, Esau?", "The 11th of Jacob\u2019s sons was this guy whose brothers sold him into slavery and smeared goat blood on his \u201ccoat of many colors\u201d to fool Jacob into believing he was dead. PS\u2014Ben Carson thinks he stored grain in the pyramids.", "This daughter of Jacob was raped by a Canaanite named Shechem, leading Jacob\u2019s sons to kill him and plunder his city."], "subcategory": "Religion", "category": "Religion", "answers_formatted": ["<b><u>Jacob or Israel</u></b>", "<b><u>Joseph</u></b>", "<b><u>Dinah</u></b>"], "acceptable": [["Jacob or Israel", "Jacob or Israel"], ["Joseph", "Joseph"], ["Dinah", "Dinah"]], "promptable": [[], [], []], "rejectable": [[], [], []], "metadata": ["", "", ""]}, {"leadin": "This author\u2019s early short story \u201cDefender of the Faith\u201d was collected in Goodbye, Columbus. FTPE:", "answers": ["Philip Roth", "Portnoy\u2019s Complaint", "Prague"], "parts": ["What American writer created the alter-ego Nathan Zuckerman in books like The Ghost Writer.", "Roth\u2019s first major fame came after the publication of this 1969 novel, in which the title character, Alexander, describes his interior life to Dr. Spielvogel.", "One of Roth\u2019s Zuckerman novels is titled for this city\u2019s orgy; Roth himself traveled to this central European capital to champion writers like Milan Kundera."], "subcategory": "American Literature", "category": "Literature", "answers_formatted": ["<b><u>Philip Roth</u></b>", "<b><u>Portnoy\u2019s Complaint</u></b>", "<b><u>Prague</u></b>"], "acceptable": [["Philip Roth", "Philip Roth"], ["Portnoy\u2019s Complaint", "Portnoy\u2019s Complaint"], ["Prague", "Prague"]], "promptable": [[], [], []], "rejectable": [[], [], []], "metadata": ["", "", ""]}, {"leadin": "In arthropods, hemolymph is analogous to this substance, which in humans is roughly fifty-five percent plasma and forty-five percent cellular elements. For 10 points each:", "answers": ["blood", "leukocytes [or white blood cells]", "William Harvey"], "parts": ["Name this fluid whose cellular elements include platelets, which aid in clotting.", "These cells that are found in blood protect the body from diseases and infections. Examples of these cells include basophils, eosinophils, and neutrophils.", "This man, an English physician, discovered the circulation of blood in the early 17th century."], "subcategory": "Biology", "category": "Science", "answers_formatted": ["<b><u>blood</u></b>", "<b><u>leukocytes</u></b> [or <b><u>white blood cells</u></b>]", "<b><u>William Harvey</u></b>"], "acceptable": [["blood", "blood"], ["leukocytes", "leukocytes", "white blood cells"], ["William Harvey", "William Harvey"]], "promptable": [[], [], []], "rejectable": [[], [], []], "metadata": ["", "", ""]}, {"leadin": "Michele di Lando was a leader of the revolt of the Ciompi [CHAHM-pee]. For 10 points each:", "answers": ["guilds", "Florence", "Bonfire of the Vanities [or Falo delle vanita]"], "parts": ["That revolt was led by men who labored in fields which didn\u2019t have the protection of these medieval organizations that controlled work in specific disciplines in a town.", "The revolt of the Ciompi occurred in this Italian city-state, which fought against the Papal States in the War of the Eight Saints, and was later ruled by members of the Medici family.", "Florence was home to this 1497 event, in which Girolamo Savonarola and his supporters burned thousands of sinful objects, including works by Boccaccio and Botticelli."], "subcategory": "European History", "category": "History", "answers_formatted": ["<b><u>guilds</u></b>", "<b><u>Florence</u></b>", "<b><u>Bonfire of the Vanities</u></b> [or <b><u>Falo delle vanita</u></b>]"], "acceptable": [["guilds", "guilds"], ["Florence", "Florence"], ["Bonfire of the Vanities", "Bonfire of the Vanities", "Falo delle vanita"]], "promptable": [[], [], []], "rejectable": [[], [], []], "metadata": ["", "", ""]}, {"leadin": "The main island of this archipelago is actually named Unguja, though it is informally known by the name of the entire island chain. FTPE:", "answers": ["Zanzibar", "Dodoma", "Mount Kilimanjaro"], "parts": ["What is this archipelago off the coast of Tanzania, the namesake city of which features Stone Town, and which engaged in a 40-minute war with England?", "Zanzibar is semi-autonomous, but it is still governed from this capital of Tanzania, which fully replaced Dar es Salaam in 1996?", "This tallest mountain of Africa lies in the northeast of Tanzania."], "subcategory": "Geography", "category": "Geography", "answers_formatted": ["<b><u>Zanzibar</u></b>", "<b><u>Dodoma</u></b>", "Mount <b><u>Kilimanjaro</u></b>"], "acceptable": [["Zanzibar", "Zanzibar"], ["Dodoma", "Dodoma"], ["Mount Kilimanjaro", "Kilimanjaro"]], "promptable": [[], [], []], "rejectable": [[], [], []], "metadata": ["", "", ""]}, {"leadin": "This type of series is convergent if the absolute value of the common ratio is less than one. FTPE:", "answers": ["geometric series", "1.8 [or 9/5; or nine-fifths] {Sum = First Term / (1-Ratio)}", "Archimedes"], "parts": ["Name this type of series whose common ratio between consecutive terms is constant.", "You have twenty seconds for the following bonus part. The sum of an infinite geometric series that begins positive three, negative two, positive four-thirds, et cetera, has this value.", "A geometric series was used in this man's proof that the area of a parabolic segment equals four-thirds times the area of the largest inscribed triangle. This author of Quadrature of the Parabola also wrote The Sand-Reckoner and The Cattle-Problem."], "subcategory": "Math", "category": "Science", "answers_formatted": ["<b><u>geometric</u></b> series", "<b><u>1.8 {Sum = First Term /}</u></b> [or <b><u>9/5</u></b>; or <b><u>nine-fifths</u></b>]", "<b><u>Archimedes</u></b>"], "acceptable": [["geometric series", "geometric"], ["1.8 {Sum = First Term /}", "1.8 {Sum = First Term /}", "9/5", "nine-fifths"], ["Archimedes", "Archimedes"]], "promptable": [[], [], []], "rejectable": [[], [], []], "metadata": ["", "1-Ratio", ""]}, {"leadin": "This compilation of stories includes \u201cThe Hunchback\u2019s Tale\u201d and \u201cThe Three Apples.\u201d FTPE:", "answers": ["One Thousand and One Nights or Arabian Nights", "frame story or narrative or device (accept \u201cframing\u201d with any of those)", "Sinbad the Sailor"], "parts": ["What is this collection of originally oral tales from around the Middle East, North Africa, Persia, and India which are told by Scheherazade to Shariyar?", "The device in which an outside narrative involves a person telling stories that are then related as a \u201cstory within the story\u201d is referred to by this term.", "The stories of this adventurer, who has his ship destroyed by huge birds called Rocs and who kills the Old Man of the Sea after serving as his slave, were added to Western versions of the One Thousand and One Nights in the 18th century."], "subcategory": "World Literature", "category": "Literature", "answers_formatted": ["<b><u>One Thousand and One Nights or Arabian Nights</u></b>", "<b><u>frame story or narrative or device</u></b>", "<b><u>Sinbad the Sailor</u></b>"], "acceptable": [["One Thousand and One Nights or Arabian Nights", "One Thousand and One Nights or Arabian Nights"], ["frame story or narrative or device", "frame story or narrative or device"], ["Sinbad the Sailor", "Sinbad the Sailor"]], "promptable": [[], [], []], "rejectable": [[], [], []], "metadata": ["", "accept \u201cframing\u201d with any of those", ""]}, {"leadin": "Chapters in this book are dedicated to the voyages of Hong Bao and Zhou Man. FTPE:", "answers": ["1421", "Ming", "Australia"], "parts": ["Name this Gavin Menzies book titled for \"The Year China Discovered America.\"", "Those voyages in addition to seven made by Zheng He mostly occurred under the reign of the Yongle Emperor during this Chinese dynasty, which also produced some nice porcelain.", "Gavin Menzies coincidentally shares his last name with a Prime Minister from this country who served from 1939 to 1941 and again from 1949 to 1966. A different PM from this country named Harold Holt was accused of being a Chinese spy after disappearing during a swim."], "subcategory": "World History", "category": "History", "answers_formatted": ["<b><u>1421</u></b>", "<b><u>Ming</u></b>", "<b><u>Australia</u></b>"], "acceptable": [["1421", "1421"], ["Ming", "Ming"], ["Australia", "Australia"]], "promptable": [[], [], []], "rejectable": [[], [], []], "metadata": ["", "", ""]}]}